You may have seen
that a couple of days ago,
we announced that we raised $3.7
million US for Nootonic,
and we secured a valuation for the
business at $20
million US.
And some of you might've been like, "Wow,
that's really cool, but what
does that mean?
And why would a business that's doing well
need to raise
money?" And I'll be honest, these
are the same questions that I had to ask.
Firstly, there are a few lessons
that everyone should take note of
when it comes to
Nootonic.
We wouldn't have been able to come out the
gates as fast as we did if it
wasn't for having strong email marketing.
And one of the main premises
that I promote in my mentorship is
that most of us
should hope to pivot at some point.
When I was a personal trainer,
I didn't expect to pivot into online PT.
When I was an online PT,
I didn't expect to pivot into writing
books.
When I was writing books,
I didn't expect to pivot into having a
business
mentorship.
It only makes sense looking backwards.
So whatever business
or industry you're in,
just make sure you're taking data, so
that when you do inevitably pivot into
another avenue, you have lots of
data that you can utilize to get yourself
off the mark. Back to the Nootonic raise.
I'm not sure if I'm allowed to tell you
this, but I'll tell you anyway.
About six to 12 months ago,
a very big business,
that we even got a little
bit giddy around, tried to buy us,
in essence.
We thought it was going to be a strategic
investment, but pretty much they said,
"We will buy you. We'll take half now,
and we'll take half in a few years." It
was
tempting, would've made Chris
and myself look like we know what we're
doing, which
we don't.
We're just winging it like everyone else.
But it was in that meeting
that we realized companies
that might want to acquire
you or invest into you don't care about
profit. They care about growth.
If anything,
we were profitable in our first year,
which we bootstrapped.
And what that means
is we put all of our own money in to start
this project.
And even in the first few years,
we had so much money tied up in stock
that we
would have to then invest more money to
diversify the stock and bring new products
in. "Oh, guys,
we're bringing out a focus blend." "That's
amazing." "We need
another $200,000 from everyone." "Great."
So we then realized at that point, if the
aim isn't to be profitable
and it's just to grow as fast as we can,
then looking at
our existing projections of sell a million
dollars of stock, have,
for argument's sake,
$2 million to then buy $2 million of stock
to then sell and have $4 million,
the curve wasn't aggressive enough
for our liking. Not only that,
when it comes to getting
that aggressive curve, you
need things like retail,
getting into shops, getting onto shelves.
You need relationships with buyers.
You need people that know what they're
doing, not Chris and I.
Chris is amazing at this podcast.
I'm great at chatting about email
marketing,
whatever it is.
So we needed to hire people,
needed to bring in talent.
And one thing that
was really smart for us would be to not
only just get a cash
injection,
which would be the same as throwing petrol
on a fire, but also to get an
injection of knowledge from people
that know this realm, and then
also other people of influence.
If you look at our lineup of the people
that have
invested,
it's like "The Avengers." I'll tell you
what, just so I don't miss any
out,
I'm going to [chuckles] quickly go
through.
Darren Cartel, we are sorry
that we spelled your name wrong.
I say we, it wasn't me
that spelled your name wrong. It was Kev.
It was Kevin. He spelled your name wrong.
So we got Kayla Itsines,
the biggest female fitness
influencer in the world.
Good friend of mine.
Seeing her for dinner tomorrow night.
Alan Barrett,
who scaled Grenade to the massive heights
that they are.
And again, those of you
that remember Grenade back in the day,
they were
pre-workout.
They didn't expect to pivot to be the
biggest-selling
chocolate bar in the UK, to the fact
that Mondelez would bloody buy them.
Dan Martell, love his stuff,
and he doesn't just have one GT3,
he has two. He has a GT3 RS and a GT3.
Sent me a nice little DM just to
emasculate me. Well done. It worked.
Cody Sanchez, absolute killer.
Met her earlier this year in LA.
Mike Thurston,
world's most controversial blood work.
You know I joked in a video
and sent him a voice note saying,
"Send me your blood
work," and he actually did. But anyway,
we'll move on to it.
There are some creators here
that I don't know, never met them,
but I look forward
to meeting them. Darren Cartel.
Paul Lalima, great friend of mine.
Jay Parker.
Seth from B Team. Ed Lawrence invested.
Ed has always been my sensei, so it was
flattering that I sat with him in Dubai,
and we're having a coffee.
I said, "Oh,
do you want to maybe invest?" He goes,
"Yeah, sure." To tell you how
well Ed's doing, when he goes, "Oh,
I'll invest this much," we're like, "Whoa,
I
don't think we can handle
that amount of investment." We had to
barter him down.
We had to say,
"Can you commit to half?" Chris Donnelly,
absolute weapon, really
inspired me to go hard on LinkedIn.
Daniel Priestley, absolute weapon,
one of my favorite people in the business
space.
Dane McDonald,
another big hitter in the fitness
education space in
Australia. George Mack,
one of the smartest brains on the
internet.
And then some other high-end investment
firms, of which
one called JDI. Now,
the reason we like JDI is rewind to
2017. My manager, Luke,
who's a shareholder in the business,
the week before his
wedding,
took me on a private jet to Ibiza for one
night with my best friends as
like a signing contract.
Now I can never leave him.
If Live Nation come
and want to do my tours, I go,
"You didn't take me to Ibiza for
one night on a jet."
But at Luke's wedding,
the big boss of JDI just
walking past me, he goes,
"I hear you went on a jet last week." I
said, "Yeah.
Honestly, it was amazing." He goes, "Well,
if you want to come on a proper private
jet,
we're going to Amsterdam next weekend." So
of course, we went. The audacity.
He said, "Well,
we can do handstands on the private jet
we're taking." Wow.
Anyway,
I wanted to talk about the raise
and talk about Nootonic because although
it is great and I appreciate all of the
sentiment of people saying it's amazing,
you also shouldn't care because we've
still not made any money.
Personally, I mean. The valuation
is still speculative, and until we hit
20 million in revenue,
I don't think we should even celebrate
yet.
Although there's more skin in the game
and we've got more capital to play with,
the
risks are now higher.
Every single investor into the business,
to me,
it feels like a responsibility
that we have to continue to grow this
and branch
out and to get into territories
and to do the marketing and do the PR.
It's no longer just the four of us.
It's now bigger, wider, and more serious.
And I will not be celebrating until we've
reached the heights that we want to, or
even better yet, maybe we divest.
Maybe in three to five years,
someone comes
along, maybe like Coca-Cola,
and Coca-Cola says, "Oi,
we're taking half," and I
get to pay off my parents' mortgage
and my sister's mortgage
and my own mortgage
and anyone else's mortgage
that I care about.
So it's great, but at the same time,
this is just the beginning.
Can't take the foot off the gas, which
is relatively stressful, but it's a very
enjoying project nevertheless because this
has been built off just content
creation, email marketing,
the exact same thing
that everything else is built on.
From the talks to the books to the fitness
app to this, it's all the same.
I wish I could say it requires more
or it's more complex, but it's not.
The same process happens.
You have to accrue enough goodwill from an
audience by
putting content out
and helping their problems to get them to
the point that they
buy your product.
You're better off getting someone's email
address than you are
selling them something direct, which
is why we'll always try and go direct to
customer as much as we can rather than
going through TikTok or Amazon where we
don't get contact information.
Because every time a new product comes
out, you want
the ability to contact people.
How you sell something
is how you sell everything.
How you market something
is how you market everything.
And although this is incredibly exciting,
I just want to remind people this today.
The first thing that you launch
and get good at and spend years trying to
market is often the most boring,
the least exciting.
But as you develop as a marketer,
as a personal brand, as a creator, as a
content creator,
your potential for things to [whistles]
only increases with time.
I started off selling sets
and reps in person in a budget gym in
Bracknell.
I then sold sets, reps, workouts,
and accountability online.
I then sold 300 pages of paper between two
nice covers that you could buy
in WHSmith.
I then moved into a consultancy business,
which I'm going to have to do
today,
of helping small creators monetize their
businesses.
I then set up a fully-fledged nootropic
business.
I'm now an investor in Manual in the UK,
one of the world's largest
TRT services. But all the cool,
exciting shit up here would be nothing
without
all the boring yards and the hard work
and the slow-paced growth over years
on social media. So wherever you
are in your journey,
get excited because if you
keep at it and keep doing what you're
doing, the cool stuff is to come.
But I definitely earned my stripes in the
early days doing the boring stuff when no
one cared, no one watched the content,
no one read my blogs, no one reacted to my
videos,
and no one signed up to my email
newsletter.
If you can stick with the suck for long
enough,
eventually you get to a point where
you can pivot and you can do really well
from it.
I will put a link in the description for
you to try some Nootonic, and beneath
that, I'll put my email address,
my personal email address.
If you don't love the product for whatever
reason, give me your feedback, and I'll
refund you out my own personal money.
That's not me going into Stripe
and hitting Refund.
It's me getting my Monzo card out
and saying,
"Here you go." It seems like a pretty
crazy offer to give the world of the
internet, especially when loads of people
don't like you, but I suppose to me,
that's what we could call on
LinkedIn founder behavior.
Enjoy and thanks to everyone that's going
to click on the link and buy some